<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Life on Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</title>
    <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/tags/daily-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daily Life on Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</description>
    <image>
      <title>Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</title>
      <url>https://upendra1997.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:29:34 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://upendra1997.github.io/tags/daily-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diversifying Career</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/diversify-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:29:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/diversify-career/</guid>
      <description>A write-up about future career choices</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I aim for a high impact career, and the more I contemplate this, the more I realize it cannot be achieved by sticking to one field alone.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been entrenched in the computer science realm for some time, with a side interest in machine learning/data science. While my past roles have mainly revolved around fintech or logistics, I believe achieving greater career impact necessitates cross-pollination across different domains, blending diverse ideas to enhance my work.</p>
<p>As I ponder various future career or study paths, several interests have caught my attention:</p>
<ol>
<li>Delving into hardware intricacies, such as battery firmware, embedded systems, and GPU programming.</li>
<li>Exploring the biological world, potentially leveraging my existing knowledge through resources like <a href="https://github.com/ossu/bioinformatics">https://github.com/ossu/bioinformatics</a>.</li>
<li>Expanding my involvement in machine learning/data science, transitioning from occasional dabbling to full-time engagement.</li>
<li>Venturing into civil services to address societal issues with my technological expertise.</li>
<li>Establishing and scaling my own business, offering insights into delegation, negotiation, hiring, execution, finance, and more.</li>
<li>Exploring commerce and finance to understand wealth management, savings, growth, and the role of technology, for instance, via platforms like <a href="https://zerodha.com/varsity/">https://zerodha.com/varsity/</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>I remain eager to contribute more, learn more, and assist across various fields, industries, and scenarios.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting Yourself Out</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/putting-yourself-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/putting-yourself-out/</guid>
      <description>putting myself out on internet</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have never been consistent with my writing and I wish to change it to become better at writing; and Internet is a place where we can express ourself. so this is me being accountable and putting myself out.</p>
<p>Now, I will be trying to write about:</p>
<ol>
<li>daily-life</li>
<li>things I learned</li>
<li>explaining something</li>
<li>snippets</li>
<li>anything else</li>
</ol>
<p>I will be trying to stick with it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
