<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</title>
    <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</description>
    <image>
      <title>Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</title>
      <url>https://upendra1997.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 21:41:38 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://upendra1997.github.io/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Into Computer Science</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/getting-into-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 21:41:38 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/getting-into-cs/</guid>
      <description>A little writeup about how I got into CS</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Throughout my childhood, I held a keen interest in computers, particularly in gaming. However, the technical\science aspects didn&rsquo;t initially captivate me.</p>
<p>Back in 2010, acquiring new games was a challenge due to limited internet access. We relied on friends with installation CDs, DVDs, or pendrives. Unfortunately, scratched disks often led to checksum errors or missing files, which forced us to download DLLs/files from the internet to fix issues.</p>
<p>Encountering language barriers(English is not my first language) or difficult game levels led us to seek <a href="https://www.cheatengine.org/">cheat engine</a> for assistance. It was through this pursuit that I was introduced to Lua, although my attempts at mastery were unsuccessful. Nonetheless, I learned to utilize basic features like memory scanning to manipulate in-game values, enabling me to progress in game, by freezing my health, or getting large pool of money.</p>
<p>My formal introduction to programming languages occurred during high school (2013-2015), where I immersed myself in HTML, Java, and other languages introducted in the syllabus. I delved into course materials fervently, which reflected positively in my academic performance in computer-related subjects.</p>
<p>Upon entering college for my bachelor&rsquo;s degree (2015-2019), my first year was uneventful as I focused on academic excellence. However, the second year introduced me to a world of possibilities through friends who introduced me to courses, competitive programming, hackathons, and more. This reignited my passion for learning new things, and I avidly pursued knowledge.</p>
<p>Few resources that helped me were:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ossu/computer-science">https://github.com/ossu/computer-science</a></li>
<li>Steven Halim&rsquo;s CP book: <a href="https://cpbook.net/">https://cpbook.net/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262046305/introduction-to-algorithms/">https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262046305/introduction-to-algorithms/</a></li>
<li><a href="https://teachyourselfcs.com/">https://teachyourselfcs.com/</a></li>
</ol>
<p>These resources not only aided my learning but also paved the way for my initial job opportunities. Despite my skepticism regarding the quality of indian college education, I acknowledge its role in facilitating exploration, fostering friendships, and providing time for personal development.</p>
<p>Subsequent learning occurred on the job and through interactions with colleagues. I remain committed to continuous learning, always seeking to expand my skill set and find joy in the process.</p>
<p>And you know what? Its just getting started. Here&rsquo;s to a lifetime of curiosity and adventure!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversifying Career</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/diversify-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:29:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/diversify-career/</guid>
      <description>A write-up about future career choices</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I aim for a high impact career, and the more I contemplate this, the more I realize it cannot be achieved by sticking to one field alone.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been entrenched in the computer science realm for some time, with a side interest in machine learning/data science. While my past roles have mainly revolved around fintech or logistics, I believe achieving greater career impact necessitates cross-pollination across different domains, blending diverse ideas to enhance my work.</p>
<p>As I ponder various future career or study paths, several interests have caught my attention:</p>
<ol>
<li>Delving into hardware intricacies, such as battery firmware, embedded systems, and GPU programming.</li>
<li>Exploring the biological world, potentially leveraging my existing knowledge through resources like <a href="https://github.com/ossu/bioinformatics">https://github.com/ossu/bioinformatics</a>.</li>
<li>Expanding my involvement in machine learning/data science, transitioning from occasional dabbling to full-time engagement.</li>
<li>Venturing into civil services to address societal issues with my technological expertise.</li>
<li>Establishing and scaling my own business, offering insights into delegation, negotiation, hiring, execution, finance, and more.</li>
<li>Exploring commerce and finance to understand wealth management, savings, growth, and the role of technology, for instance, via platforms like <a href="https://zerodha.com/varsity/">https://zerodha.com/varsity/</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>I remain eager to contribute more, learn more, and assist across various fields, industries, and scenarios.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting Yourself Out</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/putting-yourself-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/putting-yourself-out/</guid>
      <description>putting myself out on internet</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have never been consistent with my writing and I wish to change it to become better at writing; and Internet is a place where we can express ourself. so this is me being accountable and putting myself out.</p>
<p>Now, I will be trying to write about:</p>
<ol>
<li>daily-life</li>
<li>things I learned</li>
<li>explaining something</li>
<li>snippets</li>
<li>anything else</li>
</ol>
<p>I will be trying to stick with it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
