<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</title>
    <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</description>
    <image>
      <title>Blog | Upendra Upadhyay</title>
      <url>https://upendra1997.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:29:34 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://upendra1997.github.io/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Diversifying Career</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/diversify-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:29:34 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/diversify-career/</guid>
      <description>A write-up about future career choices</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to have a high impact from my career and and more I think about trying that, I feel that it cannot be done by simply following one field.</p>
<p>I have been in computer science field for a while and have dabled in machine-learning/data-science on the side. All the jobs that I have taken were also aligned to the either fintech or logistics. But I feel that to have better impact on my career, I require cross pollination of different fields to mix-match different ideas from different fields and add value to whatever work I do.</p>
<p>I have been considering multiple future career/studiets that wish to pursue and there are few of the things that I have been interested in:</p>
<ol>
<li>Working more closely to hardware, like: battery firmware, embedded systems, GPU programming, etc.</li>
<li>Learning more about biological world, and I feel that the way to step into it through learning it with something that I already know, like: <a href="https://github.com/ossu/bioinformatics">https://github.com/ossu/bioinformatics</a></li>
<li>I have been dabbling in machine-learning/data-science, and also have done multiple courses and certifications, but I never got to work on it full time; so having an opportunity there might also help me.</li>
<li>Working in civil services and seeing the issues the people and government faces and trying to help them with my experience in technology.</li>
<li>Starting my own business and growing it, which I think will teach me about lots of things like Delegating, Negotiating, Hiring, Execution, Finance, etc.</li>
<li>Working in Commerce and Finance to learn managing, saving and growing money and how technology can help in doing it better. For examle: <a href="https://zerodha.com/varsity/">https://zerodha.com/varsity/</a></li>
</ol>
<p>I still feel like I can do more, learn more, help more and hope that I get to work in all kind of fields, businesses and situtations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting Yourself Out</title>
      <link>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/putting-yourself-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 10:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://upendra1997.github.io/posts/putting-yourself-out/</guid>
      <description>putting myself out on internet</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have never been consistent with my writing and I wish to change it to become better at writing; and Internet is a place where we can express ourself. so this is me being accountable and putting myself out.</p>
<p>Now, I will be trying to write about:</p>
<ol>
<li>daily-life</li>
<li>things I learned</li>
<li>explaining something</li>
<li>snippets</li>
<li>anything else</li>
</ol>
<p>I will be trying to stick with it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
